ABHINAV SONONE

+91 9175541102 | Pune, Maharastra | Email | Github | Linkedin | Social

SUMMARY

Abhinav is a passionate data science enthusiast with a strong interest in analytics and data-driven decision making. With a multifaceted approach to data, he enjoys conducting research, wrangling data, building models and effectively communicating the results.

EDUCATION

CGPA 9.4*, Data Science, IIT Madras*
Grade 75%, B.E. Mechanical, SCOE Pune
10+2, 85%, Board of Higher Secondary Education, Maharashtra
10, 98%, Board of Secondary Education, Maharashtra

EXPERIENCE

IIT-Madras: Academic Mentor for Statistics- Intern

09/2022 - 12/2022

- **Subject:** Mentoring and Teaching 'Statistics II [BSCMA1004]' to a fellow cohort.
- Skillset: Hypothesis Testing, Bayesian Statistics, Analytics, Statistical Modeling etc.

Xicon International Ltd- Mumbai

02/2017 - 11/2017

- Role: Design and Sales Cross Functional Engineer
- Worked alongside the sales and marketing team to identify new opportunities, address technical challenges, and provide insights to clients.

PROJECTS

- GREEN-AG: Developed an emissions estimation engine for agricultural farms, using machine learning
 algorithms to predict emissions based on factors like location, crop types, and fertilizer usage. [Inclusive
 Data Hackathon 2023 by Digital Page and Capgemini]
- **SENTIMENT-ANALYSIS**: Using machine learning algorithms, built a model capable of accurately determining whether a review conveys a positive, negative, or neutral sentiment. [ACADEMIC]
- IMDB Actor Network Analysis: Utilized Python to collect and preprocess data, and Kumu for visualization and analysis in exploring actor networks, demonstrating proficiency in data-driven insights and cutting-edge tools [ACADEMIC]
- Warranty Box: India's one-of-its-kind app to claim warranty across different products. Real-time warranty tracking and timely alerts. Digital and hassle free ticketing service. Awarded as one of top 8 projects in Hack-o-Pitch 2022 IITM.[HACKATHON]
- Surveillance Robot (Academic Project- SCOE): Built a wireless manually controlled surveillance robot. It
 consists of a single unit which monitors the places for various emergency conditions and provides video
 feedback via web interface. [ACADEMIC]

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, SQL, Matlab

Web Stack: HTML, CSS, Flask, Jinja2, PyHTML, BeautifulSoup

Visualisation: Tableau, PowerBI, Kumu, Flourish, Excel, Google Sheets **ML Libraries**: Sklearn, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn, Tensorflow **Other**: Problem solving, Analytics, Statistics, Communication, Leadership

CERTIFICATIONS: Microsoft Azure AI-900, NPTEL-Design Thinking, NPTEL- Numerical Optimization

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won Inclusive Data Hackathon 2023- Organised by Digital Page and sponsored by Capgemini.
- Awarded 2nd prize at ISHRAE Pune chapter 2017- Presented Review Paper on Good Building Physics for Sustainable Environment.
- TFWS Scholarship: Awarded to meritorious students for UG Studies.

Other:

- SOLVING THE ASSIGNMENT VS LEARNING PROBLEM A DESIGN THINKING CASE
- Won first prize in AWS Gameday organized as part of Capgemini Data Hackathon.
- Campaigns Volunteer at Make a Difference Pune: Designed Campaigns Strategy, Fundraising Campaigns and Creating Compelling Narratives and Stories